# **Bshr Ramadan**

Computer & Software Engineer

- O Damascus, Syria

in bshr-ramadan

bshrram

Computer Engineer with 3 years of professional work experience in backend development. Experienced with a wide range of development languages, frameworks and tools, including Node.js, Golang, Rest, Graphql, Microservices, AWS, ...etc.

Delivered successful projects and have experience working on large scale projects. Possesses strong problemsolving skills and is able to quickly identify and resolve issues. Excellent collaboration skills, and able to work as part of a team or independently.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Larsa (May 26, 2022 - Present)

Backend Developer, UAE-Remotely, Full-time

- Designed and implemented a SaaS e-commerce service with Golang and No-SQL architecture, providing
  high performance and low resource usage, and communicating with tens of other existing microservices in
  the company system through synchronous and asynchronous protocols, which are managed with
  Kubernetes.
- Worked with a team of expert coders to write maintainable code and maintain existing software to improve performance and fix bugs, using many technologies like: Golang, Node.js, SQL, NoSQL, Docker,
- Followed OWASP practices to improve web applications security.
- https://www.larsa.org/

Stowk (movecar) (April 14, 2021 - Present)

Software Engineer, US-Remotely, Part-time

- Developing and supporting applications, database integration, and new feature enhancements.
- Collaborated with the remote team of engineers on moving to a new scalable infrastructure, automating deployments and improving performance, reducing costs by around 80% in result.
- Participated effectively in meetings and provide valuable suggestions for technical and business processes.
- Some skills used: `Node.js, Golang, AWS, Serverless-Stack(Sst), MongoDB, ApolloGraphql-Federation`
- https://movecar.com/

Unifi.Solutions (November 14, 2020 - April 14, 2021)

Back-End Developer, Canada-Remotely, Full-time

- Handled and implemented the back logic of much software including a chat application, an IOT platform with thousands of devices, an app organizing Islamic procedures in Canada, and home automation platform.
- Worked in contributed with a team and as a leader of a sub-team.
- Some skills used: `Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Socket.io`
- https://www.unifi.solutions

iEducate (September 30, 2019 - January 21, 2021)

Developer, Damascus-Syria, Contract

Worked with team on creating a new iEducate app, admin dashboard and their backend, using: `Node.js -

React - ReactNative - Loopback.js - MongoDB`

https://ieducate.co

Freelancer (March 31, 2017 - February 28, 2019)

Web developer, Contracts

- The first real-world experience was in 2017 by participating in developing <u>SuperMarkBot</u> with a team of university colleagues, using `Node.js MongoDB Microsoft bot framework`.
- Then worked with <u>BrainSocket</u> Team on a REST API for a website, using `node.js Loopback.js mongoDB`.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Kids and Adolescents Programming Marathon - KPM Coach

(April 30, 2019 - January 04, 2020)

https://svuonline.org/en/training/program-training-children-and-youths

Treepon state and south

(November 19, 2014 - April 03, 2018)

Social Manager, Copywriter

RBCs Team (2014 - 2018)

https://www.linkedin.com/company/rbcs-team/

SKILLS

**Programming Languages** 

Golang, Javascript, Typescript, Python, C++

Web Technologies

Node.js, Go, Rest-Api, GraphQl-Api, MongoDB, SQL, React.js

**Cloud Technologies** 

AWS Serverless Lambda functions, AWS CDK(infrastructure as code), Containerizing with Docker, Orchestration with Kubernetes, Github-Actions & jenkins as CI

## **LANGUAGES**

English
Intermediate

Native

**Arabic** 

## **EDUCATION**

Damascus University

(October 31, 2014 - September 30, 2020)